Leo：From the bottom of our hearts, we promise that from here on out
Vanessaの脅威が去ってから3か月
It's already been three months since the crisis that Vanessa threatened the world with was averted...
Leo：今後は秘密裏に古代文明を使用せず
A.R.C. stated that they would abolish the Library's facilities
A.R.C.はLibraryの廃止を発表し
Leo：and will be transparent with all the content of our research
Leo：研究内容においても公開し  透明性の高い経営を目指してまいります
and use other types of server technology to replace the operations of the virtual internet
現在は異なるサーバー技術で  神経ネットワークを運営している
Leo：Starting today, we will implement serious changes to our internal structure
Leo：また社内改革を行い
Leo：For the development of society and humanity
Leo：社会と人類の発展のために
Of course, lots of people found this unacceptable and denounced the organization
愛する者を失った人をはじめ
Leo：we will seriously reconsider our position in society and the direction we are headed...
Leo：今一度経営方針を見直し……
Especially those who lost their loved ones as a result of what happened
現実を受け入れられない人はまだ多い
But after a period of time most people returned to their normal lives
だがすべては時間とともに忘れられ
Time gradually diluted all that had occurred
大多数の人々は  徐々に元の生活を取り戻しつつある
After graduating from university, NEKO became a professional streamer musician
NEKO はアカデミーを卒業し  現在は編曲や実況などで生計を立てている
Besides her normal content of music, games and random gossip
実況の内容は音楽のことからゲーム  ゴシップまでさまざまだ
NEKO#ΦωΦ：Yo-ho! NEKO's here!
NEKO#ΦωΦ：やっほー！NEKO だよー！
she also started a new series
新たに開設したチャンネルでは
where she actively goes out to help the victims that were affected by Vanessa
Vanessaの事件で被害を受けた人々の  援助を積極的に行っている
Victim：We don't need help from you internet addicts. Please, go away...
被害者：ネット中毒の人の助けはいらないんで  帰ってください……
Although she is constantly rejected, she never gives up
拒絶されてもめげることなく
She used money she made from her music and streams to set up a foundation
音楽と配信による収入を使い慈善団体を設立
that donates to the people affected and related illnesses
被害に遭った人々のために  募金などの活動も行っている
Xenon started playing with a band again and got back on the stage to perform
Xenonは音楽活動を再開し  ステージへと戻ってきた
NEKO can always be seen among the crowd
観客席にはNEKOの姿も見受けられる
NEKO#ΦωΦ：Not bad~!
NEKO#ΦωΦ：おつー！
As for Xenon's sister Shannon,
そしてXenonの妹Shannonは
she gradually shed the effect that the virtual internet had on her
事件後徐々に神経ネットワークの影響から脱し
and her condition started to improve
病状も回復に向かっている
A.R.C. kept begging Xenon to return
A.R.C.はXenonに復帰を求めているものの
But no matter how generous their offers were, no matter what position they promised
どれほどいい待遇や役職を用意されようと
Xenon refused to accept
Xenonは首を縦にはふらない
After the dissolution of Baro,
バローが瓦解し  JOEZ Cafeもその地位を徐々に上げている
JOE's way of doing things became more and more like Saxon's
JOEにもSaxonの面影が  見て取れるようになってきた
Mr. Neumann decided to move to Node 13,
ConneRはNode13への移住を決意
continuing to research the unsolved mysteries of his ancestors with Sasha
Sashaと共に未だ解き明かされぬ  祖先の謎について研究を続けている
Humanity was still curious about ancient technology and yearned to learn more
人類の古代文明に対する興味が  失われたわけではない
The missions of A.R.C.'s Exploration Team continued
A.R.C.の探査隊はいまだ任務続行中だ
ConneR：Oh? You again?
ConneR：なんだね？君か？
ConneR：Keep up the hard work
ConneR：ご苦労様
Rin was able to break free of A.R.C.'s control,
RinはA.R.C.のコントロールから解放され
concealing her Architect identity and living with Sagar
アーキテクトであることを隠しつつ  Sagarと共に暮らしている
She also returned to Node 03 to look for her past memories
またNode03で自身の思い出を  探して回っている
Rin：Ah! Oh...
Rin：わっ！あ……
Rin：I'm s-so sorry!
Rin：ご、ごめんなさい！
Rin：Wah!
Rin：きゃっ！
Daigo：Chief, here's the part you asked for
Daigo：リーダーお探しの部品です
Nora returned to Kyuu Hou Kai and led research in various fields of medicine
Noraは玖凰會へと戻り  医療技術の研究を続けている
Nora：Thank you, just put it there
Nora：ありがとう　そこに置いておいて
all the while trying to repair ROBO_Head
それと同時にROBO_Headの修理も続行中だ
Nora："NORA"
Nora：「NORA」
Helena was unable to accept the loss of PAFF and Noah, remaining mired in sorrow,
HelenaはPAFFとNoahがいない事実を  受け入れられず
all alone
ひとり悲しみに暮れている
Hayato remained in the "music world", as promised,
Hayatoは約束の「音楽世界」に留まり
missing Kaori through music
音楽を通して薫を思う日々を過ごしている
Though sorrow and regret remains,
悲しみはまだ消えない
everyone is still working hard to live their lives
だが人々は懸命に生きている
The world still turns,
世界は回り続ける
just as before.
これまでも　これからも